RAMESH ADHIKARI

PhD Student at Augusta University

Augusta, Georgia, USA | radhikari@augusta.edu

Website: ramesh-adhikari.github.io | GitHub:ramesh-adhikari | LinkedIn: adramesh

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Ph.D. student at the School of Computer and Cyber Sciences, Augusta University, under the guidance of Dr. Costas Busch. My research focuses on Distributed Algorithms and Blockchain Technology. With four years of industry experience as a Software Engineer, I bring both academic expertise and practical knowledge to my work.

EDUCATION

School of Computer and Cyber Sciences, Augusta University

Ph.D. in Computer and Cyber Sciences

Pokhara University

Masters of Science in Computer Engineering

Tribhuvan University

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

Augusta, Georgia, USA

Aug 2022 - Present

Kathmandu, Nepal

2018 - 2021

Kathmandu, Nepal

2013 - 2017

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Ramesh Adhikari, and Costas Busch. Lockless Blockchain Sharding with Multiversion Control, SIROCCO 2023 (2023)

Ramesh Adhikari, and Suresh Pokharel. Performance Evaluation of Convolutional Neural Network Using Synthetic Medical Data Augmentation Generated by GAN. International Journal of Image and Graphics (2021): 2350002

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Assistant | Augusta University | Augusta, Georgia, USA

Aug 2022 - Present

Working on the distributed algorithm and blockchain technology, mainly on sharding in blockchain to solve the scalability issue, under the supervision of Dr. Costas Busch.

Graduate Student | Nepal College of Information Technology | Kathmandu, Nepal

2020 - 2021

Worked on machine learning and deep learning projects under faculty members to complete master's research.

SERVICE

- Invited Reviewer, ACM SIGMIS Computers and People Research 2024 (SIGMIS CPR 2024)
- Invited Reviewer, The 43rd ACM Symposium on Principles of Distributed Computing (PODC 2024)
- External Reviewer, Transactions on Mobile Computing, 2024
- Invited Reviewer, 31st International Colloquium On Structural Information and Communication Complexity (SIROCCO 2024)
- \bullet External Reviewer, The 6^{th} IEEE International Conference on Blockchain (Blockchain 2023)
- External Reviewer, IEEE Transactions on Network and Service Management (2022)

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | Sanima Bank | Kathmandu, Nepal

May 2019 - Jun 2022

- Developed web applications for commercial banks
- Integrated API and web services
- Developed Batch Script and SQL query to automate the process

Software Engineer | SmartMobe Solutions Pvt. Ltd | Kathmandu, Nepal

Feb 2018 - April 2019

- Collaborated with a 30-member team to develop cutting-edge APIs for mobile and web apps
- Researched new tools and technologies, implementing improvements for efficiency and automation

ACHIEVEMENTS AND PARTICIPATION

- Received \$650 NSF Student Travel Awards for CANS conference (Nov 2023)
- Participated in International Conference on Cryptology and Network Security (CANS) (Nov 2023)
- Attended The Southeast Regional Programming Languages Seminar 2023 (Oct 2023).

- Presented a paper at the 30th International Colloquium on Structural Information and Communication Complexity (SIROCCO 2023) in Alcala De Henares, Madrid, Spain (June 6-9, 2023)
- Received \$1000 travel award from the Graduate School, Augusta University, to present a paper at SIROCCO 2023 (Mar 2023)
- Presented a poster at the 3rd annual workshop on Emerging Data Science and Cyber Data at Augusta University (Mar 2023)
- Received \$100 NSF travel award for the 3rd Data Science Workshop at Augusta University (Feb 2023)
- Attended the International Symposium on Distributed Computing (DISC) conference (Oct 2022)
- Received \$340 NSF travel award for the (DISC) conference (Oct 2022)
- Received the Star Performance Excellence Award at Sanima Bank Ltd (2021)
- Granted a full scholarship for a Master of Science in Computer Engineering from Pokhara University (2018)
- Served as a member of the Kathford FOSS Community at Kathford International College
- Achieved First Runner-Up in a software competition at Kantipur Engineering College (2015)

SKILLS

Programming languages, Libraries, Tools: Python | Go | C | C++ | JavaScript | PHP | Tensorflow | MySQL | SQL server | Shell Scripting

Broad Skills: Distributed Algorithm | Distributed System | Blockchains | Algorithmic Analysis | Web Scraping | Database Design | Machine Learning | Cloud Computing | Problem Solving